Guide to the Ernie O'Malley Papers AIA.060
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series X. Diaries, Notes and Research, 1922-1963
  - Notebook: "Cross Slabs", circa 1939, undated; cuid36825 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    This notebook contains 226 pages, 176 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: "P", circa 1939, undated; cuid36826 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Green patterned notebook containing sketches, writings, and research notes on Spanish art and artists, including Francisco Goya.
    This notebook contains 264 pages, 204 of which have writing.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1932-1935, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Tan notebook with tan binding containing photographs, published writings, and annotations concerning early Christian art and architecture of castles, churches, and monasteries in Co. Kildare, Kilkenny, Tipperary, and Sligo.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1936-1938, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Unbound notebook containing research notes on Irish poets and dramatists, including Joseph Plunkett, George Bernard Shaw, Lennox Robinson, and Sean O'Casey.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1937-1938, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Black notebook containing research notes on archaeology and early Irish architecture, including a list of sites visited by Ernie O'Malley.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1937-1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Black notebook containing transcriptions of poems, original writings, and research notes on writers including Marcel Proust, Malcolm Cowley, John Milton, Lascelles Abercrombie, Hart Crane, Edith Wharton, William Butler Yeats, and T.S. Eliot.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1944, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Loose pocket notebook containing shopping lists and other personal lists.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1947, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Pocket notebook containing shopping lists and research notes about military interviews and the Irish War of Independence.
  - Notebook: untitled, circa 1956, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Loose pocket notebook containing personal lists and research notes on military interviews and the Irish War of Independence.
  - Notebook: untitled, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Black pocket notebook containing addresses, schedules, and other personal entries.
  - Notes: American [on Irish folklore and ballads], 1928-1933 (Box 15, Folder 12A)
  - Notes: Autobiography: I, circa 1944-1948 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Notes taken and collected by Ernie O'Malley in the creation of his autobiography, including reflections of his travels and life with Helen Hooker.
  - Notes: Autobiography: II, circa 1944-1948 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Notes: Autobiography: I, circa 1944-1950 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Notes taken and collected by Ernie O'Malley for the creation of his autobiography, including reflections of his travels and life with Helen Hooker. Also includes cancelled checks of Hooker and documents relating to the affidavit from the 1950 lawsuit between Hooker and O'Malley.
  - Notes: Autobiography: II, circa 1944-1950 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Notes: British overseas islands, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 16A)
    Loose notes on British overseas islands, including St. Helena, Seychelles, and Ascension Island.
  - Notes: English Literature, 1950 (Box 15, Folder 16B)
    Loose notes on English literature, poetry, and plays, ncluding the writings of Sir Walter Scott and Caradoc Evans.
  - Notes: Folklore (drawn and painted Louisburgh map), circa 1940, undated (Flat-file-folder 1, Folder TBD)
  - Notes: Folklore, circa 1940, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Photocopy of notebook containing writings of Irish folklore and Clew Bay, Co. Mayo.
  - Notes: Folklore: I, 1940s (Box 15, Folder 19)
    Transcription of 15 folktales from Clew Bay, Co. Mayo area recorded and transcribed by Ernie O'Malley. Also includes correspondence by Cormac O'Malley.
  - Notes: Folklore: II, 1940s (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Notes: Irish: General, undated (Box 16, Folder 1A)
  - Notes: Irish History, undated (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Research notes by Ernie O'Malley on medieval history and history of western Ireland, including Connaught.
  - Notes: Irish History, undated (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Notes: Irish History: I, undated (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Irish History: II, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    No Subnote Content
  - Notes: Irish Christian Monuments, 1954 (Box 16, Folder 5A)
  - Notes: Irish History: Irish War of Independence, circa 1928-1952 (Box 16, Folder 5B)
  - Notes: Irish History: Irish Civil War, circa 1928-1952 (Box 16, Folder 5C)
  - Notes: Irish Literature, circa 1929 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Lists of books and loose notes on Irish literature, including John Millington Synge, Lady Gregory, and Douglas Hyde.
  - Notes: Lists of books read by Ernie O'Malley, 1926-1927 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: I, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    Correspondence, envelopes, postcards, newspaper clippings, and loose notes concerning a variety of subjects, including literature, finances, writings, and books, in addition to a handwritten list of neighbors with lands close to Burrishoole Lodge, Newport, Co. Mayo.
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: II, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: III, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: IV, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: V, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: VI, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: VII, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Notes: Miscellaneous: VIII, circa 1929-1952 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Notes: Music, circa 1940-1946 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    Loose notes on music, including writings on Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Johann Sebastian Bach, Jean Sibelius, Josquin de Pres, and other composers.
  - Notes: Travel Expense, circa 1925-1926 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Notes: untitled, circa 1963 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Pink notebook with ivory binding containing an inventory of the library remaining in Ernie O'Malley's estate following various sales occuring before and after his death.
  - Notes: untitled [Irish Literature?], 1929-1950 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Series XI. Clippings and Publicity, 1895-2002
  The series is arranged chronologically.
  This series includes newspaper clippings, book reviews, magazine features, advertisements, book covers and correspondence relating to Ernie O'Malley, his literary output and posthumous publications. Many of the clippings in this series were collected by O'Malley and reflect his general interests in art, literature, poetry, theatre and current affairs. Clippings also relate to international affairs and historic events including the Second World War, Spanish Civil War and Anglo-Irish relations. O'Malley collected articles of interest from both American and European newspapers including, The New York Times, Irish Independent and Irish Press. This series also contains clippings detailing O'Malley's funeral, as well as, book reviews and other items pertaining to the publication of On Another Man's Wound and its German translation, Rebellen en Irlande. Additional items in this series relate to the publicity of books published after his death by O'Malley's son Cormac O'Malley and Richard English including Prisoners: The Civil War Letters of Ernie O'Malley and Richard English's Ernie O'Malley: IRA Intellectual.
  - Index to Clippings and publicity, 2010 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Clippings collected by Ernie O'Malley, 1895-1949 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: various including family, death notice, donation of papers to University College Dublin, 1922-1990 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Clippings collected by Ernie O'Malley (see index for list), 1921-1948 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: wounding and capturing of O'Malley, 1922-1957 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Reviews of Ernie O'Malley books I, 1928-1992 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Reviews of Ernie O'Malley books II, 1928-1992 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Clippings re: Marriage O'Malley-Hooker; society clippings, 1935-1936 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Irish, English and American press, 1935-1937 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: Irish, English press including articles on Charles Lindburgh, Eamon DeValera, Fred Aiken, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: Irish, English and American press, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: Review of Army without Banners, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Clippings and reviews: International Arts: I, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Clippings and reviews: International Arts: II, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Clippings and reviews: Arts and similar, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Clippings, mostly Irish: Art, History, Current Affairs: I, 1936-1948 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, mostly Irish: Art, History, Current Affairs: II, 1936-1948 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, mostly Irish: Art, History, Current Affairs: III, 1936-1948 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: International Affairs, Spain, Art, Ireland, 1936-1961 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: reviews Army without Banners - New York, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: reviews Army without Banners - Massachusetts, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: reviews Army without Banners - United States, 1937 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Clippings and publicity: On Another Man's Wound (Irish Press), 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Clippings and publicity: On Another Man's Wound, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Clippings and publicity: On Another Man's Wound, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: German Language, 1938-1939 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: Reviews of Ernie O'Malley and works, 1940-2002 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Clippings - Irish Press, 1949 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Clippings collected by Ernie O'Malley, 1953-1954 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Clippings: Ernie O'Malley Funeral, 1957 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Publicity: Raids and Rallies, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Clippings: Book Reviews: Prisoenrs: Civil War Letters of Ernie O'Malley, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - Clippings: Book review: IRA Intellectual, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Clippings: various topics; from Irish Press, The New York Times, The Observer, Sunday Times, 1935-1936, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Publicity on Biography: IRA Intellectual, 1998 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Index to Clippings Addition [Box 40, Folder 29 through Box 41, Folder 37], undated (Box 40, Folder 29)
  - Clippings: Literature, Russian, 1920-1934 (Box 40, Folder 30)
  - Clippings: Literature, American, 1924-1932 (Box 40, Folder 32)
  - Clippings: Literature, American, 1924-1932 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: Literature, French, 1926-1934 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Clippings: Literature, English, 1925-1941 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Clippings: Literature, Irish, 1926-1945 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Clippings: Literature, Norwegian, 1928 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Clippings: Literature, Greek and Roman, 1930-1935 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Clippings: Literature, German, 1932-1934 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Clippings: Literature, Chinese and Japanese, 1932-1934 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Clippings: Literature, Spanish and Mexican, 1934 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Clippings: Reviews, biographical, 1926-1934 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Clippings: Reviews, Reference Works, 1926-1935 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Clippings: Reviews, Literature: General, 1924-1934 (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - Clippings: Reviews: Articles on Ancient Cultures, 1924-1934 (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Clippings: Art, Architecture, 1924-1937 (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - Clippings: Psychology, 1925-1935 (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - Clippings: Theatre [mostly Irish], 1925-1939 (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - Clippings: Music, Dance, 1926-1935 (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - Clippings: American Indians, 1926-1935 (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: Philosophy, 1930-1934 (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - Clippings: Education, 1922-1944 (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - Clippings: American, Icelandic, 1927-1931 (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Mexico, 1927-1930 (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: National, International, 1927-1935 (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: "Drama, Screen, Music, Dance, Art, Radio," New York Times, Mar 20, 1938 (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - Clippings: American, Contempo, Dec 15, 1931 (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - Clippings: The American Spectator, Jan 1934 (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - Clippings: The Magazine of Art, 1939-1946 (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - Clippings: The Nation, Jul 1941 (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - Clippings: What's New, Feb 1951 (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - Clippings: Saturday Evening Post, Sep 20, 1952 (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - Clippings: The New Yorker, May 15, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 31)
  - Clippings: The New Statesman and Nation, Sep 11, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 32)
  - Clippings: Time and Tide, Oct 4, 1941 (Box 41, Folder 33)
  - Clippings: The Times Literary Supplement, Mar 26, 1954 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - Clippings: L'Illustration, Nov 10, 1923 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Clippings: La France Libre, Dec 1946-Jan 1947 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Clippings: Journal of the Royal Society of Antiquaries of Ireland, 1933 (Box 41, Folder 37)
- Series XII. Arts Material, 1918-1955
  Notebooks, notes, works, lectures, clippings, magazine articles, photographs, postcards, reprints of artwork, brochures, sketches, exhibition catalogues, theatre programs and printed materials reflecting O'Malley's interest in painting, sculpture, architecture, archeology, music and theatre throughout Europe, Mexico and the United States. Many of the clippings, magazine articles and reprints were collected by O'Malley as research for his articles and essays on painting, sculpture, archeology, architecture and other related topics. A substantial number of art catalogues and theatre programs were deposited at University College Dublin by O'Malley's son, Cormac O'Malley, in 1974. Photocopies of the aforementioned items remain in this series, along with nearly 50 original art catalogues and theatre programs. Also included in this series are more than 200 copies of photographs taken by O'Malley, Helen Hooker O'Malley and others from Mexico and Ireland. Of special interest are notes taken by O'Malley during a series of interviews he conducted with organizers of the Irish Exhibition of Living Art during the 1940s. O'Malley's interest in art criticism encouraged him to embark on series of interviews with some of Ireland's most prominent modern artists including, Evie Hone, Jack Hanlon, Louis le Brocquy, Norah McGuinness, Nano Reid and many others. Works by other authors are filed at the end of this series.
  - Art Materials: Index, 2010 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Brochure: "Retrospective Emmanuel Gondouin", 1935 (Box 42, Folder 19)
  - Catalogues: Belgium, 1946 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Catalogues: England: I, 1942-1955 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Catalogues: England: II, 1942-1955 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: I (copies), 1936-1944 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: II (copies), 1936-1944 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: I (copies), 1945-1951 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: II (copies), 1945-1951 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: III (copies), 1945-1951 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Catalogues: England: I, 1939-1948 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Catalogues: England: II, 1939-1948 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Catalogues: England: III, 1939-1948 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Catalogues: England: IV, 1942-1955 (Box 41, Folder 40)
  - Catalogues: France: I, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Catalogues: France: II, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: I, 1926-1951 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: II, 1926-1951 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: III, 1926-1951 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: IV, 1936-1944 (Box 41, Folder 38)
  - Catalogues: Ireland: V, 1945-1955 (Box 41, Folder 39)
  - Catalogues: Italy, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Catalogues: Scotland, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 41)
  - Catalogues: United States: I, 1928 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Catalogues: United States: II, circa 1932-1935 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Clippings: French Art, 1946-1947 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Clippings: Irish Art and Artists: I, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Clippings: Irish Art and Artists: I, undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Clippings: Mexican Art and Artists (in Spanish), 1931 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Clippings: Mexican Art and Artists, 1928-1949 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Clippings: Mexican Art and Artists, 1943-1947 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Clippings: European Painting and Sculpture I, undated (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Clippings: European Painting and Sculpture II, undated (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Clippings: European Painting and Sculpture III, undated (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Clippings and reprints: European Painting and Sculpture I, undated (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Clippings and reprints: European Painting and Sculpture II, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture I, 1926-1946 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture II, 1926-1946 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture III, 1926-1946 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture IV, 1926-19746 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture I, 1927-1950 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture II, 1927-1950 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture III, 1927-1950 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Clippings and reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture IV, 1927-1950 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Notebook: European Art History, 1937-1938 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Notebook: Irish Archeology and History, undated (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Notebook: Archeology and Architecture, 1921-1947 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Notes: Art - European Painting, 1937, undated (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Notes: Art - European Painting, circa 1936-1937 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Notes: Art - European Painting, undated (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Notes: Art - Florentine Drawings, undated (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Notes: Art - French Artists, circa 1946-1947 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Notes: Art - "History of Modern Art", circa 1944-1948 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Notes: Art - Interviews with Irish Artists, circa 1945 (Box 20, Folder 19)
    Notes from Ernie O'Malley's interviews with Irish artists, including Evie Hone, Mainie Jellet, Ralph Cussack, Mae Guinness, Judy Boland, Nick Nicholls, Norah McGuinness, and Louis L Brocquy.
  - Notes: Art - Irish Art and Artists, undated (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Notes: Art - Italian Art and Artists, circa 1925-1926 (Box 20, Folder 21)
    Ernie O'Malley's diary notes and travel expenses from Italy, in addition to notes on Italian art and artists, including Giotto, Bozzoli, del Castagne, and Masolino da Panicale.
  - Notes: Art - Mexican Art, Artists and Archeology, 1930-1947 (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Notes: Art - Mexican Travels, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Notes: Art - various topics, 1932-1945 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Notes: Irish History, circa 1938-1946 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Notes: Music, circa 1938-1946 (Box 20, Folder 26)
  - Notes: Art - various: I, circa 1938-1946 (Box 20, Folder 27)
  - Notes: Art - various: II, circa 1938-1946 (Box 20, Folder 28)
  - Photographs: Early Christian Sculpture and Architecture: I, undated (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - Photographs: Early Christian Sculpture and Architecture: II, undated (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Photographs: Early Christian Sculpture and Architecture: III, undated (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Photographs: French Art and Fashion design, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Photographs: Mexican Art: I (copies), 1931 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Mexican Art: II (copies), 1931 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Postcards: Art (Box 33)
  - Postcards: Art: Portraits; Collections: Louvre (Box 34)
  - Postcards: Art Collections (sets of postcards from museums) (Box 35)
  - Postcards: Art Collections (sets of postcards from museums) British Museum, Musee de Cluny (Paris), undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Postcards: Architecture (divided by country) (Box 36)
  - Postcards B-W: Boats; Events; Landscapes including Europe, Ireland, Les Pyrenees, Mexico, United States; Unidentified; People, Political (Irish); Various; with Writing (by Ernie O'Malley) (Box 37)
  - Printed Materials: Irish Medieval Art and Architecture, 1925, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Printed Materials: Irish Archeology and Ancient Architecture, Pprehistoric crafts, 1918-1936 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Programs: Concerts: Dublin, 1944-1948 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Programs: Concerts: London, 1944-1948 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Programs: Concerts: Paris, 1930 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Programs: Concerts: United States, 1929-1933 (Box 42, Folder 17)
  - Programs: Theatre performances in England, Ireland and United States: I (copies), 1925-1951 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Programs: Theatre performances in England, Ireland and United States: II (copies), 1925-1951 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Programs: Theatre performances in England, Ireland and United States: III (copies), 1925-1951 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Programs: Theatre (originals), 1928-1946 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Programs: Theatre: Abbey Theatre, 1926-1951 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Programs: Theatre: Gaiety Theatre, 1942-1951 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Programs: Theatre: Dublin Gate Theatre, 1938-1948 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Programs: Theatre: Lyric Theatre (London), 1947-1948 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Programs: Theatre: Olympia Theatre (Dublin), 1943 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Programs: Theatre: Dublin Drama League, 1926-1942 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Programs: Theatre: University College Dublin Dramatic Society, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Programs: Theatre: Dublin University Players (Trinity College Dublin), 1945 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Programs: Theatre: American Theatre, 1925-1946 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Programs: Theatre: The Players Theater (Dublin), 1945-1951 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - Publicity Publications, 1945-1948 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Reprints: European Painting and Sculpture: I, undated (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Reprints: European Painting and Sculpture: II, undated (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Reprints: European Painting and Sculpture: III, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Works: Article "Arts in Ireland" draft, 1945-1946 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Works: Article "Fifth Exhibition of LIving Art" (draft), 1947 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Works: Article "Portrait of a Woman" draft, circa 1946 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Works: Article "Jack B. Yeats" draft, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Works: Article "Louis le Brocquy" draft, 1946 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Works: Review of Exhibition of Evie Hone's works in Dublin (draft), circa 1945 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Works by Others: Higgins, Sheila E., 1947 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Works by Others: Judge, Eugene of Caher, 1943-1945 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Works by Others: unknown, circa 1945-1947 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Arts Material: Oversize
    - Clippings and Reprints: European Painting and Sculpture, 1929-1946 (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Clippings and Reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture, 1944-1946 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Clippings and Reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture I, 1927-1950, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Clippings and Reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture II, 1927-1950, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Clippings and Reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture (A-B), 1937-1947 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Clippings and Reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture (C), 1937-1947 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Clippings and Reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture (D), 1937-1947 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Clippings and Reprints: European and American Painting and Sculpture (E-F), 1937-1947 (Box 39, Folder 8)